Guide to the Adrienne Cohen Papers, 1963-2000 and undated RL.00241
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Adrienne Cohen papers
1963-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cohen, Adrienne
RL.00241
5 Linear Feet
Copy writer and advertising executive for several agencies primarily in the Atlanta, Ga. area. The Adrienne Cohen Papers span the years 1963-2000 and include print advertisements, copy designs, direct marketing mailings and brochures, storyboards, audiotapes, 16mm and 35mm films of radio and television commercials that document Cohen's work as an advertising copy writer and creative executive. Companies represented include Marschalk, Young & Rubicam, and McCann-Erickson. Clients include Coca-Cola, Drackett, Eastern Airways, Gulf Oil, and Texize. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
2000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Adrienne Cohen Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012.
Collection Overview
The Adrienne Cohen Papers span the years 1963-2000 and include print advertisements, copy designs, direct marketing mailings and brochures, storyboards, audiotapes, 16mm and 35mm films of radio and television commercials that document Cohen's work as an advertising copy writer and creative executive. Companies represented include Marschalk, Young & Rubicam, and McCann-Erickson. Clients include Coca-Cola, Drackett, Eastern Airways, Gulf Oil, and Texize.
Collection Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files, Printed Material, Print Advertisements, Storyboards, and Audiovisual Materials.
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Bud Titsworth Commercials
Joy Golden Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Albert B. Stridsberg Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Carroll Carroll Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Hilton Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. John F. Devine Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Lois Gaeta Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Maury Holland Papers
Advertising -- History; Advertising; Atlanta (Ga.); Radio scripts; 16mm; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies; Advertising -- United States -- History; Radio advertising; Atlanta (Ga.) -- Commerce; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising executives; 35mm; Audiocassettes; McCann-Erickson Worldwide; Young & Rubicam; Gulf Oil Corporation; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Drackett Company; Eastern Airways; Cohen, Adrienne; Cohen, Adrienne; Coca-Cola Company
- General Files
  - Biographical information, undated (Box 1)
  - McCann Atlanta creative work plan--Hard sell, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Print advertisements, 1964-1988 and undated (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Aid Atlanta; Atlanta Market Center; Atlanta Perimeter Mall; CNN; Cone Corduroy; Eastern Airlines; Georgia Trend; JWI Group; Lady Remington shaver; Milliken Place; Omni Hotels; Peachtree Center; RB Management Services; St. Ives Country Club]
  - Print copy designs, undated (Box 1)
    [Beverly Bremel Silver Shop; Café Plaza; Chick-Fil-A; Church's Fried Chicken; French Quarter Suites; Johson Wires; Sabena Belgian World Airlines]
  - Printed Material, Direct Marketing and Sales Promotion
    - Aid Atlanta, circa 1993 (Box 1)
    - Atlanta & Georgia Magazine, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Atlanta Merchandise Mart, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Atlanta Opera, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Carter Center, undated (Box 1)
    - Chick-Fil-A, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Coca-Cola, 1962-1987 (Box 1)
      [Includes waitress training pamphlet]
    - Comfort Management, Inc., undated (Box 1)
    - Equitable Building, undated (Box 1)
    - Equity Office, 1990s (Box 1)
    - Forest Fair Mall, undated (Box 1)
    - Galleria Specialty Mall, undated (Box 1)
    - Gardiner & Theobald, undated (Box 1)
    - Georgia Pacific (Olympics merchandising), 1991 (Box 1)
    - High Museum of Art, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Kodak Imaging Services, 1995 (Box 1)
    - LJ Hooker Developments (Forest Fair Mall), undated (Box 1)
    - Mindis International, undated (Box 1)
    - Omni Hotels, undated (Box 1)
    - RB Management Services, undated (Box 1)
    - Rising Star Outreach, 1990s (Box 1)
    - U.S. Postal Service, Why Wrap? Promotion, undated (Box 1)
    - Vinings Jubilee, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Wrangler/Blue Bell, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Radio scripts, 1964-1971 and undated (Box 1)
  - Speech written for Maurey Kelley, Eastern Airlines, circa 1970s (Box 1)
  - Storyboards
    - Coca-Cola, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Drackett (O-Cedar; Pleascents; Windex), 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - General Foods (Birds Eye; Jell-o), 1964-1967 (Box 1)
    - Lady Remington shaver; Modess; Playtex Baby Nurser, 1965 and undated (Box 1)
- Large Format Materials
  - Mounted Advertisements (Box 2)
    - Breck Skin Conditioner, Face Cream, undated (Box 2)
    - Eastern Airlines, undated (Box 2)
    - General Foods/Birds Eye, undated (Box 2)
    - Wilkins Tailored Jeans, undated (Box 2)
  - Print Copy Designs
    - Christian Children's Fund, undated (Box 2)
    - O-Cedar, undated (Box 2)
  - Printed Material, Direct Marketing and Sales Promotion
    - Coca-Cola/McDonald's Summer Olympics tie-in, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Wilkins Tailored Jeans, undated (Box 2)
  - Mounted Advertisements (Box 3)
    - Aldon Carpets, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Atlanta Symphony Orchestra/Primavera Music Festival, undated (Box 3)
    - Citizens and Southern Bank,undated (Box 3)
    - Eastern Airlines, undated (Box 3)
    - Modess, undated (Box 3)
    - Omni Hotels, undated (Box 3)
  - Print Copy Designs
    - O-Cedar, undated (Box 3)
  - Print Advertisements (Box 4)
    - Aldon Carpets, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Arrow Mach II shirts, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Atlanta Fine Arts Tours, undated (Box 4)
    - Breck Moisturizing Lotion, undated (Box 4)
    - Charter Brooke Hospital, undated (Box 4)
    - Citizens and Southern Bank,undated (Box 4)
    - CNN, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Coca-Cola, 1963-1980s (Box 4)
    - Coets, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Eastern Airlines, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - Excelan, 1988 (Box 4)
    - General Foods/Birds Eye, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Georgia Pacific, 1991 (Box 4)
    - LJ Hooker Developments, undated (Box 4)
    - Modess/Meds, undated (Box 4)
    - Mindis International, undated (Box 4)
    - Omni Hotels, undated (Box 4)
    - Pleascents (Drackett), 1968 (Box 4)
    - Remington/Lady Remington shaver, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
    - Sarong So-Free (girdle), undated (Box 4)
    - Software Link, circa 1989 (Box 4)
    - Turner Boot Camp, circa 2000 (Box 4)
    - Wilkins/Fancy Props and Rumble Seat Jeans, circa 1980s (Box 4)
  - Newsprint advertisements
    - Coca-Cola, circa 1962 (Box 4)
    - Cone Corduroy, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Eastern Airlines, undated (Box 4)
    - Galleria Specialty Mall, 1987 (Box 4)
    - General Foods/Birds Eye, 1964-1968 (Box 4)
    - Richard Bowers & Co., undated (Box 4)
    - Rivermore Park, undated (Box 4)
    - Sarong, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Vinings Jubilee, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Print Copy Designs
    - Bellows Gin, undated (Box 4)
    - Breck Face Cream, undated (Box 4)
    - Coca-Cola, undated (Box 4)
    - General Foods/Birds Eye, undated (Box 4)
    - Modess/Meds, undated (Box 4)
    - Party Shine Spray Wax, undated (Box 4)
    - Pleascents, undated (Box 4)
    - Sabena Belgian World Airlines, undated (Box 4)
  - Storyboards
    - Coca-Cola, 1962 (Box 4)
    - General Foods/Birds Eye, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Gulf Oil Company, undated (Box 4)
    - Johnson & Johnson/Band Aid, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Playtex Baby Nurser, undated (Box 4)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1963-1977 and undated
  - Atlanta Symphony: Primavera XXME-1331. Undated. 16mm. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Cheer Detergent: Judy Alone 452. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Cheer Detergent: Judy Alone 453. Undated. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Citizens and Savings Bank: Graduation. Undated. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Citizens and Savings Bank: Vacation. Undated. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: TV2-114. 1963. 1963. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Christmas TV6-111. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Christmas TV2-112. Undated. 0:20 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Contest FS6-127. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Contest FS-212. Undated. 0:20 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Contest SKAY-83. Undated. 0:14 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Horn TVS-132. Undated. 0:20 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Punch FS6-122. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Punch FS-207. Undated. 0:20 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Save 'Em and Swap 'Em FS6-125. Undated. 35mm. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Coca-Cola: Save 'Em and Swap 'Em TV6-160, TV2-161. 1964. 2:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines 433-30. Undated. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Atlanta II. 1971. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (2 reels) (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Atlanta III. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Atlanta/Ebenezer Baptist Church. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (3 reels) (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Atlanta I/II/III; Chicago II; Charlotte I; San Juan II; New York III (Orson Welles narrating). Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 7:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Bahamas I. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Baltimore I. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Charlotte. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Charlotte; Raleigh-Durham; Miami. 1971. 1/4 audio reel. 3:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Chicago III. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Chicago; Charlotte; Atlanta III; Atlanta II; Dallas; New York; Houston; San Juan. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 8:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio 16 spots. 1971. 1/4 audio reel. 16:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Disney Campfire. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Houston III. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Jacksonville. 1971. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Los Angeles II. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Louisville I. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Miami II. 1971. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Miami III. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio New Orleans. 1971. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio New Orleans I; Houston I; Charlotte. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 3:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio New York I. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio New York III. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio Philadelphia; Houston; Boston; Portland; Winston-Salem; Louisville; Dallas; St. Louis. 1970. 1/4 audio reel. 8:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio San Juan. 1971. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (2 reels) (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio San Juan I. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio San Juan II. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Airlines: Destination radio St. Louis I. Undated. 1/4 audio reel. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Game. Undated. 16mm. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - General Foods/Birds Eye: Fruit Continental. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - General Foods/Birds Eye: Tasti Fries. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Gulf Oil: Binoculars 633. Undated. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Gulf Oil: Binoculars/Special End 678. Undated. 0:30 (Box 5)
  - Gulf Oil: Hurry Up and Wait 6683. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Gulf Oil: Service Station/Watch the Clock 661. Undated. 1:00 (Box 5)
  - Gulf Oil/Disney Magazine: Appaloosa Horse 660. Undated. 1:00 (3 reels) (Box 6)
  - Gulf Oil/Disney Magazine: Girl on Bridge 647. Undated. 1:00 (Box 6)
  - Gulf Oil/Disney Magazine: Winchester Horse 694. Undated. 1:00 (2 reels) (Box 6)
  - O-Cedar. Undated. 1:00 (2 reels) (Box 6)
  - Radio Advertising Bureau (Orson Welles narrating). Undated. 1:00 (Box 6)
  - Remington/Lady Remington shaver: Christmas Telephone 362. Undated. 1:00 (4 reels) (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Airborne Grease NM6R-2090. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Another Way ZMNG-2060. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Baby NM6R-2070. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Collars and Cuffs ZMNG-2030. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Fan Toss NM6R-2110. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Good Morning ZMNG-2040. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Grease Toss NMGR-2100. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Hamburger ZMNG-2050. Undated. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: New Fawn. 1977. 0:30 (Box 6)
  - Texize/Grease Relief: Spaghetti NMGR-2080. Undated. 0:30 (2 reels) (Box 6)
  - Various: Birds Eye and More (Young & Rubicam). Undated. 10:00 (Box 6)
- Direct Marketing Ephemera
  - Department of Economic Development, Developer's Day invitation with wind-up chattering teeth toy, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Shadowood Office Park tour invitation, bottle opener in box, Undated. (Box 7)